Inventory of the Stan Skalski Papers 1966-1968
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Stan Skalski Papers 1966-1968
Special Collections Research Center
01/Mss. Acc. 2009.516
1.00
This collection consists of letters, 1966-1968, written by U.S. Army Private First Class Stan Skalski to his fiancee Caren Brereton in Philadelphia, as well as biographic material. Earlier letters concern Skalski's basic training at Fort Jackson, Georgia and Fort Gordon, Georgia, and later his airborne training at Fort Benning, Georgia and Fort Bragg, North Carolina. Skalski describes various training exercises and his overall acclimation to army life, but also writes at length about personal matters. He frequently mentions family members and mutual acquaintances in Philadelphia, as well as wedding plans. Letters written during Skalski's service in Vietnam describe the activities of his patrol near the Phan Rang Air Base, located in then South Vietnam. Skalski discusses guard duty on base and encounters with the Viet Cong in the surrounding area. In addition to these written correspondences, the collection also includes biographic material, such as two postcards from Saigon and a boarding pass for the 8346th Air Division, tactical airlift to Phan Rang. A scrapbook maintained by Skalski contains photographs of his military training, including what appears to be a mock Vietnamese village, as well as service related ephemera and artifacts. The collection also includes a newspaper clipping from the Screaming Eagle, a publication of the 101st Airborne Division, which mentions the activity of Skalski's patrol.
Skalski, Stan arrangement
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
The materials were acquired by Special Collections Research Center on 11/05/2009.
Biographical Note
Information about this individual or organization may be available in the Special Collections Research Center Wiki: http://scrc.swem.wm.edu/wiki/index.php/Stan Skalski.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of letters, 1966-1968, written by U.S. Army Private First Class Stan Skalski to his fiancee Caren Brereton in Philadelphia, as well as biographic material. Earlier letters concern Skalski's basic training at Fort Jackson, Georgia and Fort Gordon, Georgia, and later his airborne training at Fort Benning, Georgia and Fort Bragg, North Carolina. Skalski describes various training exercises and his overall acclimation to army life, but also writes at length about personal matters. He frequently mentions family members and mutual acquaintances in Philadelphia, as well as wedding plans. Letters written during Skalski's service in Vietnam describe the activities of his patrol near the Phan Rang Air Base, located in then South Vietnam. Skalski discusses guard duty on base and encounters with the Viet Cong in the surrounding area. In addition to these written correspondences, the collection also includes biographic material, such as two postcards from Saigon and a boarding pass for the 8346th Air Division, tactical airlift to Phan Rang. A scrapbook maintained by Skalski contains photographs of his military training, including what appears to be a mock Vietnamese village, as well as service related ephemera and artifacts. The collection also includes a newspaper clipping from the Screaming Eagle, a publication of the 101st Airborne Division, which mentions the activity of Skalski's patrol.
Arrangement of Materials
This collection is arranged into three boxes. The first two boxes contain Skalski's written correspondences, arranged by folder into chronological order. The third box contains Skalski's scrapbook.
Additional Information
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Can openers; Certificates; Instructions (document genre); Letters (correspondence); Photographs
Topical Term:
Courtship--United States--History--20th century.; Insignia.; Military bases--Photographs; Postcards.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975--Personal narratives, American
Detailed Description of the Collection
- id67521 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, October 1966; id67514 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, November 1966; id67515 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, December 1966; id67516 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, January 1967; id67517 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, February 1967; id67518 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, March 1967; id67519 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, April 1967; id67520 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- id67522 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, May 1967; id67523 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, June 1967; id67524 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, July 1967; id67525 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, August 1967; id67526 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, September 1967; id67527 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, October 1967; id67528 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, November 1967; id67529 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, December 1967; id67530 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, January 1968; id67531 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, February 1968; id67532 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, March 1968; id67533 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, April 1968; id67534 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, June 1968; id67535 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, undated; id67536 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- id67538 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook, undated; id70476 (Box 3)